Register of the George D. Jenkins papers
Hoover Institution Archives
George D. Jenkins papers
1893-2014
69015
Hoover Institution Archives
35 manuscript boxes, 4 card file boxes, 5 oversize boxes, 23 microfilm reels (21.5 linear feet)
Writings, notes, correspondence, minutes of meetings, ordinances, reports, pamphlets, clippings, other printed matter, and data cards relating to political, economic, cultural, and social affairs in Nigeria, in general, and Ibadan and the Yoruba, in particular. Includes drafts of a book, The Price of Liberty, by Kenneth W. J. Post and George D. Jenkins.
Jenkins, George D.
Post, Kenneth W. J.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were initially acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1969, with increments received in 2011 and 2015.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
George D. Jenkins, an American political scientist, was born in Wyoming in 1934. After receiving his B.A. from Whittier College in California, he went to Berlin as a social worker. He served in a refugee camp for two years, which led to a year at the Otto Suhr Institut (Hochschule fuer Politik) at the Free University of Berlin, with a German Academic Exchange Fellowship in 1958 and 1959.
Jenkins lived in Ibadan, Nigeria from August 1962 to August 1963 and conducted research on colonial politics at the Nigerian Institute of Social and Economic Research (NISER). During his stay in Ibadan, he conducted interviews with various well-known Nigerian politicians, including Akinpelu Obisesan, Bishop Akinyele, his brother the Olubadan, and the daughter of Adegoke Adelabu.
In 1965, Jenkins received his Ph. D. in Political Science from Northwestern University. He taught political science at the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA), University of California, Berkeley (UCB) and Stanford University (1964-1970). He was also the founder and co-editor of African Urban Notes (1966-1968).
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of George D. Jenkins include speeches and writings, correspondence, the original draft of a book, The Price of Liberty, written by Jenkins with Kenneth W. J. Post, ordinances, and biographies of various individuals who were involved in the de-colonization process of Nigeria, a literal who's who of Nigeria politics of the 1960s.
Adelabu, Adegoke, 1915-1958.; Ibadan (Nigeria)--Politics and government.; Nigeria--Politics and government.
- Office Files, 1962, 1965 (Boxes 1, 36)
  - Business cards and notes, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 15)
  - Telephone directory, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Correspondence, 1962-1989 (Boxes 1-2, 36-37)
  - Abner, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Adeoye, Adisa, 1963 (Box-folder 36: 16)
  - African Studies Association, 1989 (Box-folder 36: 17)
  - Akinyele, A. B. (Bishop), undated (Box-folder 36: 18)
  - Akinyele, Isaac Babalola, 1963 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Akinyele, Peter, 1964 (Box-folder 36: 19)
  - Aligwekwe, Evalyn, 1965 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Apter, David E., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Ayorinde & Oloko, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 20)
  - Bascom, William, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Benoy, R. F., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 21)
  - Blair, John, undated (Box-folder 36: 22)
  - Blanksten, George, 1963 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Bob, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 23)
  - Booth, Frances, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 24)
  - Bower, Allen, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 25)
  - Brigstocke, C. C., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 26)
  - British Council, 1965 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Brown, William, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Burke, Fred G., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - C., Roger, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 27)
  - Campbell, Donald T., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Carter, Gwendolen M., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Caterham School, 1965 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Center for Research Libraries, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 28)
  - Chief Igun, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Chief Information Officer. The Ministry of War, London, England, 1966 (Box-folder 36: 29)
  - Coker, F. C. O., 1963 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Coleman, James, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Collerick, John P., 1965 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Collins, Robert O., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Cowan, Gray L., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Cox, H. B., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 30)
  - Crown, Agents, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 31)
  - CURA Executive Committee, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Curator, Map Library, Northwestern University, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Curton, Philip, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Danielson, Elena S., 1989 (Box-folder 36: 32)
  - Deputy Secretary, Ibadan City Council, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 33)
  - Dickinson, Norman, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 34)
  - Dike, K. O., 1963 (Box-folder 36: 35)
  - Dood, W., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 36)
  - Duncan, Peter D., 1965 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Dunlop, J. M. M., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 37)
  - Elgee, C. H., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 38)
  - Fani-Kayode, R. A., 1963 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Farrell, Barry R., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Fischer, M., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Foltz, William, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Former District Officers, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 39)
  - Foster, Luther H., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 40)
  - Frewer, Louis B., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 41)
  - Frknapp, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 42)
  - Garrett, Kathleen, 1969 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Gwam, C. Lloyd, 1964 (Box-folder 36: 43)
  - Hadoke, G. D. F., 1964 (Box-folder 36: 44)
  - Halasz, D., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Hamilton, Ruth S., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Hamon, Leo, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Hanna, William, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Hatch, W., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 45)
  - Helleiner, G. K., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Herskovits, Melville, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - Hofchie, undated (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - Houy, Leo Van, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 36)
  - Humfrey, L. E. H., 1965 (Box-folder 36: 46)
  - Hunter, Ted L, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - Iweanya, S. N., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - Jacobi, Gerald, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - Kaplan, Philip, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - Kelsen, Martin, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - Kenney, S., undated (Box-folder 36: 47)
  - Keving, J., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 42)
  - Kopytoff, Igor, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 43)
  - Krager, Joan M., 1975 (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - L., Kenneth G., 1965 (Box-folder 37: 2)
  - Lapage, Dora V., 1966 (Box-folder 37: 3)
  - Latunji, J. L., 1963 (Box-folder 1: 44)
  - Leland, Simeon E., 1963 (Box-folder 1: 45)
  - Lindlay, Robin L., 1965 (Box-folder 37: 4)
  - Linz, Juan, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 46)
  - Lynch, Hollis R., 1971 (Box-folder 37: 5)
  - McGrath, F. D., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 47)
  - Metcalf, D. M., 1962 (Box-folder 1: 48)
  - Metzell, Truman, 1962 (Box-folder 1: 49)
  - Minar, David W., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1: 50)
  - Mitchell, N. C., 1969 (Box-folder 1: 51)
  - Mitchell, Robert, 1965 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Molnos, A., 1969 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Morgenthau, Ruth Schachter, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Munger, Edwin S., 1969 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Newman, Robert, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Nixon, C. R., undated (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Obisesan, Akinpelu, undated (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Obisesan, Lapade, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 37: 6)
  - Okudu, S. J., 1963 (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Olunloyo, Canon, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 37: 8)
  - Pancoast, undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Panofsky, Hans E., 1962, 1987 (Box-folder 2: 9, 37: 10)
  - Partridge, Robert, 1965 (Box-folder 37: 9)
  - Porter, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Post, Ken, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Puryear, Paul L., 1965 (Box-folder 37: 11)
  - Reeve-Tucker, Ellen, 1965 (Box-folder 37: 12)
  - Ross, W. A., 1965 (Box-folder 37: 13)
  - The Royal Anthropological Institute, 1965 (Box-folder 37: 14)
  - Runyon, Charles, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Rweyemamu, Anthony H., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Schiller, Arthur A., 1962 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Schofield, I. F. W., 1966 (Box-folder 37: 15)
  - Schwab, William, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Scott, A. D., 1963 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Secretary of Public Records, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Simpson, D. H., 1964 (Box-folder 37: 16)
  - Sklar, Richard, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Snyder, Richard C., 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Sogbesan, M. O., 1964 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Stanford University, Department of Political Science, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Stitelman, Leonard, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - Tawney, John J., 1964-1971 (Box-folder 37: 17)
  - Technical Director, Fairey Air Surveys, Ltd., 1962 (Box-folder 37: 18)
  - Tishler, Barbara, 1963 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - Tordoff, William, 1967 (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - Usman, Sarki Alhaji, 1963 (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - Ward-Price, H. L., 1965 (Box-folder 37: 19)
  - Warren, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - Wauton, M. J., 1965 (Box-folder 37: 20)
  - Weiss, Peter, 1962 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Whitney, 1965 (Box-folder 37: 21)
  - Wilkes, R. L. V., 1965 (Box-folder 37: 22)
  - Williams, Gavin, 1976 (Box-folder 37: 23)
  - Williams, Mennon G., 1962 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Williams, Victor and Edmund, 1965 (Box-folder 37: 24)
  - Wilson, Meredith O., 1969 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - Wolpe, Howard, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - Wraith, R. E., 1965 (Box-folder 37: 25)
  - Zalinger, A. D., 1962 (Box-folder 2: 31)
- Speeches and Writings, 1920-2014 (Boxes 2-7, 36-39)
  - Adegoke Adelabu, Dateline, undated (Box-folder 2: 32)
  - Adelabu, second copy chronological, undated (Box-folder 2: 33)
  - "Alhaji Adegoke Adelabu: Africa in Transition,", 1965 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - Biographical notes: Appendix I, undated (Box-folder 36: 2)
  - Book review of Ashanti under the Prempehs, 1967 (Box-folder 36: 3)
  - Chief Akinyele, undated (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Colonial Witnesses: A Nigerian Biography: Akinpelu Obisesan, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 4)
  - Comments on Chuck Nixon's comments, undated (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Dateline, 2012-2014 (Box-folder 36: 5)
  - “Groups in Ibadan,”, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 6)
  - Handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Ibadan, 2012-2014 (Box-folder 36: 7)
  - "Ibadan Proposal Abstract: McElrath Papers,", 1961-1963 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Index, 2014 (Box-folder 36: 8)
  - An Informal Economy, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 9)
  - Information and memos used in rewriting, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Interview notes, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Introduction, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 10)
  - "Municipal Transport,", 1952-1954 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - “A Note on Local Sources,”, undated (Box-folder 36: 11)
  - Notes, 1934-1973
    - Ade, inquiry and aftermath, 1949-1962 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - Adelabu, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Chiefs, 1963 (Box-folder 37: 26)
    - Chieftancy, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Chieftancy, missionary impact, Ibadan Tax Committee and Council minutes, 1956-1963 (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Conversations, 1962 (Box-folder 37: 27)
    - District officers: Biographies, undated (Box-folder 37: 28)
    - "George's Thesis and Other Things,", undated (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Ibadan, undated (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - Ibadan City Council, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Ibadan Provisional District Council (IPDC) and National Council for Nigeria and Cameroon (NCNC), undated (Box-folder 6: 7)
    - Index from Atlanta, undated (Box-folder 37: 29)
    - Lecture and research, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 37: 30)
    - Local government advisors, 1963 (Box-folder 38: 1)
    - New organizations after the colonial intervention, 1963 (Box-folder 38: 2)
    - Obisesan, Akinpelu, 1963 (Box-folder 38: 3)
    - Official sources, 1963 (Box-folder 38: 4)
    - PADID (index cards), 1934-1956 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - Random Ibadan, 1934-1956 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - Tamuno thesis, 1963 (Box-folder 38: 5)
    - Typed notes, undated (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - Various councillors, undated (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - Various reports, 1963 (Box-folder 39: 2)
  - Obisesan diary, 1920-1960 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - The Price of Liberty, pp. 1-1095, undated (Box-folder 2: 34 - 3: 3)
  - The Price of Liberty, draft, pp. 1-1096, undated (Box-folder 4: 1 - 5: 1)
  - The Price of Liberty, corrections, undated (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - "The Prince of Liberty: The Life and Times of the Late Alhaji Adegoke Adelabu," afterthoughts, undated (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Research, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - A review article for possible submission to the Journal of Political Criticism, 1962 (Box-folder 36: 12)
  - Various notes, undated (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - “The Western Political Press,”, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 13)
  - "World War II materials for dissertation,", undated (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Yoruba culture, 1965 (Box-folder 36: 14)
- Minutes and Meetings File, 1937-1963 (Boxes 7-11)
  - Ibadan City Council, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 7: 6-7)
  - Ibadan District Council, 1937-1962 (Boxes 8-11)
    - Chieftancy Committee, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - Educational Committee, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - Finance Sub-Committee and Riot Damage Report, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - General Purposes Committee, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - Lands and Markets Development Committee, 1956 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - Market Development Committee, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - Ibadan District Council Meetings, 1937-1961
      - 1937-1956 (Box-folder 8: 7-8)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 8: 9)
      - 1959-1961 (Box-folder 9: 1-3)
    - Rate Committee, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Rural Development Committee, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Staff and Watch Committee, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - Special Meetings, 1952 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - Various committees, 1954 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Various committees, 1955-1962 (Box-folder 10: 1-4)
    - Works Committee, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Ibadan Native Authority, Inner Council Meetings, 1945 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Ibadan Provisional District Council, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 11: 3-4)
  - Ibadan Provisional District Council, Finance Tax Committee, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Ibadan Provisional District Council, General Purposes Committee, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Provisional Administration, Ibadan Division, Annual Reports, 1938-1956 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Report of Coker Commission of Inquiry, Vol. III, 1962 (Box-folder 11: 8)
- Subject File, 1893-1989 (Boxes 12-26, 39-40)
  - Abbatoir, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Adelabu, interviews, undated (Box-folder 12: 2)
  - Adelabu, "The Turning Point,", 1953-1954 (Box-folder 12: 3)
  - "The Adelabus, Olokuns and the Weavers at Oke-Oluokun, Ibadan," Emmanuel Oluyemi Latunji, undated (Box-folder 12: 4)
  - Adeoyo Hospital, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - Administrative offices in Ibadan, Nigeria, 1965 (Box-folder 39: 3)
  - African merchants in Lagos, 1860-1930 (preliminary list), 1963 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Agbaje Hayley (J. F.), 1950-1951 (Box-folder 12: 6)
  - Agodi Prison, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 12: 7)
  - Alafin of Oyo, 1935-1956 (Box-folder 12: 8)
  - Articles about Nigeria from dissertations, 1910-1968 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Articles by Scott Green, 1953-1961 (Box-folder 39: 6)
  - Band of Unity, Ibadan, undated (Box-folder 12: 9)
  - Book review: Selective Comments, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 39: 7)
  - British rule, 1912-1927 (Box-folder 12: 10)
  - Buses, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - C.A. analysis. West African Urbanization by Dr. Moore, 1966 (Box-folder 39: 8)
  - Census, 1962 (Box-folder 12: 12)
  - Chief Salami Agbaje, 1941-1951 (Box-folder 13: 1)
  - Chiefs, 1918-1947 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Chiefs, 1954-1963 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Chieftancy (celebrating), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Chieftancy Committee, 1950-1963 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - City planning, undated (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Colonial officers (alphabetical), 1893-1957 (Box-folder 39: 9)
  - Commissions, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Communication, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - "Comparative Urban Politics: The African Experience. A Syllabus,", 1966 (Box-folder 39: 10)
  - Conservancy services, 1956-1963 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - "Consolidated Return of All Polling Stations: Ibadan,", undated
    - General, undated (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Southwest, undated (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Northwest, undated (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Northeast, undated (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - South, undated (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - East, undated (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - "The Council: Local Government," Journal of the Western Region of Nigeria, 1956 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Councillors, 1941-1963 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Culture and tradition in Africa, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 39: 11)
  - Daily Service, Lagos, 1953-1963 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Department of Water Works, 1934-1963 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - Districts, 1908-1963 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - District officers, 1932-1966 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - "The Distribution of Power in West African Political Systems," Ken Post, 1968 (Box-folder 40: 1)
  - Divisional Council (DIVCO), 1950-1951 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Education, 1913-1960 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - "The Effective Political Units in a Transitional Society,", undated (Box-folder 40: 2)
  - Egbe Maiyegun, Ibadan, 1928-1949 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Elections, 1951-1961 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Elections results, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Encyclopedia of Education, "Grammar School,", undated (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Ethnicity, 1930-1963 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - "European Organizations: A Guide to Literature,", 1961 (Box-folder 40: 3)
  - Finance Committee, meetings and revenue estimates, 1903-1905, 1952-1963 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - "Genesis of the Nigerian Railway I," Tekena N. Tamuno, 1964 (Box-folder 40: 4)
  - Glossary, undated (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Graduated income tax, special assessment, 1953-1962 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Groups of parties, 1929-1962 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Health, 1932-1962 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - History, undated (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - "Hoover Institution Archives Holdings on Africa,", 1989 (Box-folder 40: 5)
  - Ibadan City Council: Chieftancy, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Ibadan City Council: Health and Social Welfare, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Ibadan city maps, 1966 (Box-folder 40: 7)
  - Ibadan date list, 1965 (Box-folder 40: 6)
  - Ibadan District Council, 1951-1964
    - Elections, 1954, 1958 (Box-folder 17: 1-2)
    - Estimates, 1955-1964 (Box-folder 17: 3-8)
    - Meetings, 1953 (Box-folder 17: 9)
    - Minutes, 1951 (Box-folder 17: 10)
    - Salary scales, details of revenue, and details of expenditure, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 17: 11)
  - Ibadan District Native Authority, meetings and various matters, 1938-1957 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Ibadan District Native Treasury, estimates, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - Ibadan Native Administration, estimates, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 18: 3-4)
  - Ibadan Native Administration, expenditures (Oyo Province), 1928-1931 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Ibadan Native Authority, minutes, 1950-1956 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - Ibadan Native Treasury, estimates, 1952-1955 (Box-folder 18: 7-9)
  - Ibadan Patriotic Association, 1936-1939 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Ibadan Progressive Union, 1930-1943 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - Ibadan Province Central Service, estimates, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - Ibadan Provisional District Council, 1955-1959
    - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 18: 13)
    - Education, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 18: 14)
    - Health, Rural Development and Social Welfare, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - Staff and Watch Committee, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Ibadan Tax Payers Association, 1953 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - Ibadan Town Planning Administration, 1846-1963 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Ijoba Ibile Marun, 1937 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - Index Kinshasa, 1969 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - "Industrial Location and Economic Integration in East Africa," Michael Safer, undated (Box-folder 40: 8)
  - Industrial studies at Ohio University, 1966 (Box-folder 40: 9)
  - "The Internationalization of Political Values in Stateless Societies," Robert A. Levine, 1960 (Box-folder 40: 10)
  - Iwe Itan Ibadan, undated (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - Land, 1939-1962 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Lands Committee, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Lands and markets, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - List of important lineages in Ibadan, 1965 (Box-folder 40: 11)
  - "The Local Community as an Ecology of Games," Norton E. Long, 1958 (Box-folder 40: 12)
  - Local Governments Inspectors' Conference, 1956 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Leadership, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - "London National Council for Nigeria and Cameroon (NCNC) Grand Alliance Election Communiqué No. 2,", 1953 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Maiyegun League, 1949-1962 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Maps, Africa, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 40: 13)
  - Maps, Dakar, Senegal, undated (Box-folder 40: 14)
  - Microfilms, 1964 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Minutes and correspondence, 1903-1914 (Box-folder 40: 15)
  - Minutes and correspondence, 1914-1947 (Box-folder 40: 16)
  - Miscellaneous and Adisa, 1945-1963 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Miscellaneous biographies, 1963 (Box-folder 40: 17)
  - Native Administration, estimate, Ibadan Division, Oyo Province, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Native courts, 1949-1962 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - National Council for Nigeria and Cameroon (NCNC), undated (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Nicholson Report, 1956 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Nigerian Council of Women's Societies, Western Nigeria, 1962 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Nigerian Farmers Union, 1949 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - "Notes on Careers of Present Chiefs,", 1937 (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - "Notes on Court and Pad ID,", undated (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Notes on riots, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Ordinances and by-laws, 1942-1959 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Organization, undated (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - Oyo Province, Ibadan Native Treasury, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - Party elections, NCNC Western Region Office, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 22: 4)
  - Planning, physical lands, 1936-1963 (Box-folder 22: 5)
  - Police, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 22: 6)
  - "Political Community and the North Atlantic Area," Karl Deutch, el al, 1963 (Box-folder 40: 18)
  - "The Politics of Nairobi," Herbert H. Werlin, undated (Box-folder 22: 7)
  - Population census of Nigeria, census district, Ibarapa, 1962 (Box-folder 22: 8)
  - Price, H. L. Ward, 1945 (Box-folder 22: 9)
  - Records: Criminal and civil, 1962 (Box-folder 23: 1)
  - Reforms, 1913-1914 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - Reforms, 1931-1960 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - Relations, undated (Box-folder 23: 4)
  - "Relationship Between the Adelabus and the Oluokuns at Oke-Oluokun, Ibadan,", undated (Box-folder 23: 5)
  - Religion, 1956-1964 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - Research notes: Department of Geography, University of Ibadan, 1953 (Box-folder 40: 19)
  - Roles of elites, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - Shikarsafari, undated (Box-folder 24: 2)
  - "Social Structure and Political Behavior of Senegalese Elites," William J. Foltz, 1964 (Box-folder 24: 3)
  - "Some Remarks on Urban History," Maynard W. Swanson, undated (Box-folder 40: 20)
  - Southern Nigerian Defender, 1952-1961 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - "Special Meeting of All Mogajis in Ibadan,", 1961 (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - "Statement by the Right Reverend C. Edward Crowther to the U.N.,", 1968 (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - Survey, 1962 (Box-folder 24: 7)
  - Tax, 1940-1962 (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - Tax property rating, undated (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - Tender Board File, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 25: 1)
  - Tolls, Ibadan, 1897-1903 (Box-folder 25: 2)
  - Town Planning Authority, 1939-1963 (Box-folder 25: 3)